William Tisdale

Software Developer

334-328-9186

will.tisdale.31@gmail.com

LinkedIn: in/WillTisdale/

GitHub: /WillTisdale

I decided to become a software developer because after being a client-side user, I want to be able to take that experience, make improvements, and provide excellent products/service. I would be a valuable asset to any company involved in development because I have over ten years of proven dedication and I am a very fast learner who enjoys implementing new technologies.

Technical Experience

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- BootStrap
- VCS with Git
- Paired Programming
- Thymeleaf
- Test-Driven Development
- Java SE
- MySQL
- Spring Boot Framework
- jQuery
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Java EE (Servlets, JSP)

Development Projects

Coffee Project

This project uses JavaScript to dynamically update the HTML of a webpage. Uses the functionality of sorting, adding, and removing elements from the page.

Weather Map

Uses HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, and the OpenWeatherMap API to dynamically update the current weather conditions based on the users input for location.

Ad Lister

Uses Java and the MVC design pattern for a fully functioning site where users can create an account, login, post and update ads, as well as search through all existing ads.

Professional Experience

United Parcel Service - San Antonio, TX Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2020 On Road Supervisor

- Successfully trained drivers on industry leading safe driving methods in order to achieve world class results in safety. World class safety was defined by
- Provided annual safety training for existing drivers and new driver training.
- HAZMAT certified responsible for handling leaking or damaged HAZMAT packages in the facility or on the road.

United Parcel Service - Virginia Beach, VA Jul. 2017 - Aug. 2019 Dispatcher

- Implemented plans and managed operations on Saturdays to compete with other delivery companies for the first time in the companies history.
- Used software to develop plans for all routes regarding over 6,000 delivery stops, 20,000 packages, and 1,000 pickup stops pr day in order to increase efficiency and reduce cost.

United Parcel Service - Montgomery, AL Nov. 2012 - Jul. 2017 Dispatcher

• Streamlined the process for operations involving loading delivery trucks with respect to package counts as well as employee efficiency.

Education

instruction in software development.

Associate of Science in General Education

Codeup 2021 Certificate of Completion

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 22-week full-stack Java career accelerator that provides students with 670+ hours of expert

Troy University 2016